Guide to the Collection of Advertisements that Depict American History
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- 2010 Acquisition, 1870-1994; Series II; 284
  - Collecting Cards
    - Compañía Colonial de África
      - Historia del Cacao y del Chocolate, circa 1930; 6 cards (Box 6, Folder 195)
        Cards accompanied products from the Fábrica de Chocolates Bubi.
        Incomplete set.
    - Co-operative Wholesale Society (England)
      - Western Stars, 1957; 25 cards (Box 6, Folder 196)
        Cards accompanied Jaycee Tipped Cigarettes.
    - Cope's (Firm)
      - Boats of the World, 1912; 1 card (Box 6, Folder 197)
        Cards accompanied packs of Cope's cigarettes.
    - D. Buchner & Co.
      - Police Inspectors & Captains & Chiefs of the Fire Departments, 1888; 1 card (Box 6, Folder 198)
        Cards accompanied One of the Finest tobacco.
    - D. C. Thomson & Co.
      - Adventure Picture Series, 1929; 3 cards (Box 6, Folder 199)
      - Punishment Cards, 1936; 1 card (Box 6, Folder 200)
      - Warrior Cards, 1937; 1 card (Box 6, Folder 201)
      - Badges of the Fighting Flyers, 1937 March 6; 1 card (Box 6, Folder 202)
    - Den Danske Margarinefabrik A/S
      - Samfærdselsmidler før og nu (Means of Transportation, Then and Now), 1936; 2 cards (Box 6, Folder 203)
    - Ed-U-Cards
      - Cowboys & Indians, 1949; 35 cards (Box 6, Folder 204)
    - Eilebrecht Zigaretten und Rauchtabak-Fabriken
      - Series 1. Karl Friedrich May, Winnetou, 1950; 6 cards (Box 6, Folder 205)
      - Series 4. Karl Friedrich May, Old Surehand, 1950; 6 cards (Box 6, Folder 206)
      - Series 6. Karl Friedrich May, Der Schatz im Silbersee (The Treasure of Silver Lake), 1950; 6 cards (Box 6, Folder 207)
      - Series 9. Karl Friedrich May, Der Ölprinz (The Oil Prince), 1950; 6 cards (Box 6, Folder 208)
      - Series 14. Karl Friedrich May, Schloß Rodriganda (Castle Rodriganda), 1950; 6 cards (Box 6, Folder 209)
      - Series 18. Karl Friedrich May, Winnetou III, 1950; 6 cards (Box 6, Folder 210)
      - Series 20. Karl Friedrich May, Am Rio de la Plata (On the Rio de la Plata), 1950; 6 cards (Box 6, Folder 211)
      - Series 21. Karl Friedrich May, In den Kordilleren (In the Cordilleras), 1950; 6 cards (Box 6, Folder 212)
      - Series 22. Karl Friedrich May, Halbblut (Half-Blood), 1950; 6 cards (Box 6, Folder 213)
      - Series 24. Karl Friedrich May, Der Geist des Llano Estakado (The Ghost of the Llano Estakado), 1950; 6 cards (Box 6, Folder 214)
      - Series 35. Karl Friedrich May, Der Flucher (The Curse), 1950; 6 cards (Box 6, Folder 215)
      - Series 36. Karl Friedrich May, Der Blizzard (The Blizzard), 1950; 6 cards (Box 6, Folder 216)
      - Series 42. Karl Friedrich May, Santer, 1950; 6 cards (Box 6, Folder 217)
      - Series 43. Karl Friedrich May, Sam Greenhornstreiche (Sam Greenhorn Pranks), 1950; 6 cards (Box 6, Folder 218)
      - Series 44. Karl Friedrich May, Unter Komantschen (Among the Commanche), 1950; 6 cards (Box 6, Folder 219)
      - Series 46. Karl Friedrich May, Der Pedlar (The Peddler), 1950; 6 cards (Box 6, Folder 220)
      - Series 49. Karl Friedrich May, Das Kleeblatt (The Cloverleaf), 1950; 6 cards (Box 6, Folder 221)
      - Series 50. Karl Friedrich May, Die Taube des Urwalds (The Dove of the Jungle), 1950; 6 cards (Box 6, Folder 222)
    - Evaristo Juncosa Pañella
      - Las Razas Humanas (The Human Races), circa 1930; 1 card (Box 6, Folder 223)
    - Express Weekly
      - The Wild West, 1958; 25 cards (Box 6, Folder 224)
    - Fernández y Canivell
      - Naciones del Mundo (Nations of the World), circa 1935; 2 cards (Box 6, Folder 225)
        Card series accompanied Ceregumil Tonic.
    - Fleer
      - Indian Trading Cards, 1959; 79 cards (Box 6, Folder 226-227)
        Lacks No. 56.
    - Frank Garo
      - Legends of the West, 1979; 25 cards (Box 6, Folder 228)
    - Gallina Blanca
      - Independencia EE. UU., circa 1955; 6 cards (Box 6, Folder 229)
    - Gaycon Products Ltd.
      - Red Indians, 1960; 50 cards (Box 7, Folder 230)
    - George Payne & Co. Ltd.
      - American Indian Tribes, 1962; 25 cards (Box 7, Folder 231)
        Cards accompanied G. P. Tea.
    - Godfrey Phillips Ltd.
      - Red Indians, 1927; 25 cards (Box 7, Folder 232)
    - Goodies Ltd.
      - Indian Tribes, 1975; 25 cards (Box 7, Folder 233)
    - H. Ellis & Co.
      - Untitled Series, circa 1910; 1 card (Box 7, Folder 234)
    - Hartwig & Vogel A.G.
      - Kasper u. d. Leuwutschen (Punch in the Leuwutschen), 1910; 1 card (Box 7, Folder 235)
    - Helmar Turkish Cigarettes/Turkish Trophies Cigarettes
      - Costumes and Scenery for All the Countries of the World, circa 1900; 1 card (Box 7, Folder 236)
    - Imperial Tobacco
      Cards accompanied Ogden Cigarettes.
      - Leaders of Men, 1924; 6 cards (Box 7, Folder 237)
        Subset that includes Abraham Lincoln, Christopher Columbus, George Washington, Sebastian Cabot, Thomas Alva Edison, and William Penn.
      - The Story of Sand, 1934; 1 card (Box 7, Folder 238)
    - J. Berthier, Grenoble, France
      - Untitled Series, circa 1930; 1 card (Box 7, Folder 239)
    - John H. Dockman & Son
      - Western Characters, 1910; 3 cards (Box 7, Folder 240)
        Accompanied Wild West Gum.
    - Kane Products
      - Historical Characters, 1957; 10 cards (Box 7, Folder 241)
        Subset that includes Abraham Lincoln, Billy the Kid, Daniel Boone, Davy Crockett, Edward Teach, James Wolfe, Sitting Bull, Thomas Alva Edison, Wild Bill Hickock, and William Cody.
    - Kavalier-Schuhcreme
      - Reitertypen (Types of Riders), circa 1910; 2 cards (Box 7, Folder 242)
    - Kentucky Tobaccos (Pty.) Ltd.
      - The March of Mankind, 1940; 1 card (Box 7, Folder 243)
    - L. Schaal & Cie
      - Reise um die Welt in 84 Bildern (Travel Around the World in 84 Pictures), circa 1920; 3 cards (Box 7, Folder 244)
    - Laboratoire Marie
      - Histoire Anecdotique de L'alimentation (Anecdotal History of Food), circa 1910; 1 card (Box 7, Folder 245)
    - Leaf Brands
      - Totem Pole: Talking Signs, 1962; 50 cards (Box 7, Folder 246)
      - Good Guys and Bad Guys, 1966; 72 cards (Box 7, Folder 247-248)
        Lacks No. 40, which was never issued.
    - Liebig Extract of Meat Company
      - États-Unis d'Amérique (United States of America), 1893; 6 cards (Box 7, Folder 249)
      - La Terre et ses Habitants (The Earth and Its Inhabitants), 1900; 1 card (Box 7, Folder 250)
      - Au Far-West (In the Wild West), 1908; 6 cards (Box 7, Folder 251)
      - Grandi Navigatori e Viaggiatori Italiani (Great Italian Navigators and Travelers), 1949; 1 card (Box 7, Folder 252)
      - Il Mondo Non è Tutto Uguale (II) (The World Is Not the Same (II)), 1956; 6 cards (Box 7, Folder 253)
      - Berceaux Exotiques (Exotic Cribs), 1957; 1 card (Box 7, Folder 254)
      - Le Grandi Dighe (Large Dams), 1962; 1 card (Box 7, Folder 255)
    - M. Glott Tobaksfabrik
      - Untitled Series, circa 1920; 1 card (Box 7, Folder 256)
        Cards accompanied Akaba cigarettes.
    - Mars Confections Ltd.
      - Famous Escapes from Prisons, Dungeons, Etc., 1937; 1 card (Box 7, Folder 257)
        Cards accompanied Milky Way candy bars.
    - Post Cereals
      - Hopalong Cassidy Wild West Trading Cards, 1951; 36 cards (Box 7, Folder 258)
    - Primrose Confectionery Co.
      - Cowboy, 1960; 50 cards (Box 7, Folder 259)
      - Laramie, 1964; 50 cards (Box 7, Folder 260)
    - Quaker Oats Company
      - Braves of Indian Nations, 1956; 18 cards (Box 7, Folder 261)
        Cards accompanied Quaker Pack Of Ten Cereal.
    - R & J Hill Ltd.
      - Views of Interest: British Empire Series, Canada, 1940; 40 cards (Box 7, Folder 262)
        Cards accompanied Sunripe and Spinet Oval Cigarettes.
    - Reddings Tea Co., Ltd.
      - Warriors of the World, 1962; 1 album and 1 card (Box 9, Folder 263)
      - Strange Customs of the World, 1969; 2 cards (Box 8, Folder 264)
    - Ritchie and Co.
      - American Indians, 1994; 25 cards (Box 8, Folder 265)
    - Rodríguez Hermanos
      - Untitled series, circa 1960; 1 card (Box 8, Folder 266)
    - Rowntree Mackintosh Ltd.
      - Texan Tall Tales of the West, 1977; 10 cards (Box 8, Folder 267)
    - Royal Bengals Little Cigars
      - Men of History, 2nd Series, circa 1910-1912; 1 card (Box 8, Folder 268)
      - Heroes of History, 1911; 4 cards (Box 8, Folder 269)
    - Sweetule Products Ltd.
      - The Wild West, 1960; 25 cards (Box 8, Folder 270)
        Cards accompanied Sweetule Tea.
      - National Flags & Costumes, 1962; 2 cards (Box 8, Folder 271)
    - T. G. Rovira
      - El Coyote, circa 1960; 64 cards (Box 8, Folder 272)
      - El Coyote Acorralado (The Coyote Cornered), circa 1960; 64 cards (Box 8, Folder 273)
        Complete set, but probably consists of two different printings.
      - Huracán Sobre Monterrey (Hurricane Over Monterrey), circa 1960; 64 cards (Box 8, Folder 274)
      - Billy el Niño (Billy the Kid), circa 1960; 79 cards (Box 8, Folder 275)
        Lacks album and stamp nos. 2, 11, and 42.
      - La Vuelta del Coyote (Around the Coyote), circa 1960; 64 cards (Box 8, Folder 276)
        Accompanied by the original box.
    - T. Wall & Sons Ltd.
      - Do You Know, 1965; 1 card (Box 8, Folder 277)
    - Tobacco Service Holland B. V.
      - Mensen Uit de Wereld Van Vroeger (People from the World of the Past), circa 1867, 1978; 6 cards (Box 8, Folder 278)
    - Topps Chewing Gum, Inc.
      - Rails and Sails, 1955; 6 cards (Box 8, Folder 279)
      - U. S. Presidents, 1972; 39 cards and 4 sheets (Box 9, Folder 280)
        Lacks No. 23. Benjamin Harrison, No. 29 Calvin Coolidge, and No. 35 Lyndon B. Johnson, as well as 1972 presidential candidate, No. 41 Edmund Muskie.
        Includes four fictional campaign posters.
    - Typhoo Tea Ltd.
      - Animal Offence & Defence, 1928; 1 card (Box 8, Folder 281)
      - Horses, 1935; 2 cards (Box 8, Folder 282)
    - United Dairies (Great Britain)
      - The West, 1963; 25 cards (Box 8, Folder 283)
    - Van Geetruyen & Cie
      - Indiens d'Amérique du Nord (Indians of North America), circa 1910; 6 cards (Box 8, Folder 284)
        Cards accompanied Bouillon Cibils.
    - W. Shipton Ltd.
      - Series 1. Wild West (Group 14), 1959; 3 cards (Box 8, Folder 285)
    - W.A. & A.C. Churchman Cigarettes
      - Curious Dwellings, 1926; 6 cards (Box 8, Folder 286)
    - W.D. & H.O. Wills
      - Mining, 1916; 3 cards (Box 8, Folder 287)
    - Wagner & Co.
      - Series 3. Lederstrumpf (Leatherstocking), circa 1970; 6 cards (Box 8, Folder 288)
        Cards accompanied Echte Wagner Margarine.
    - Webcosa & Co., Ltd.
      - Trail Town, 1963; 7 cards (Box 8, Folder 289)
    - Weetabix (Firm)
      - The Western Story, 1959; 25 cards (Box 8, Folder 290)
    - Yacht Cigarettes
      - Heliografering hos Indianerne (Heliographing with Indians), circa 1930; 1 card (Box 8, Folder 291)
    - Unidentified
      - Caballeria y Banderas Nacionales (Cavalry and National Flags), circa 1920; 1 card (Box 8, Folder 292)
      - Serie 384. Aus dem Indianerleben (From the Indian Life), circa 1930; 10 cards (Box 8, Folder 293)
  - Advertising Cards
    - Arbuckle Bros., New York, New York, circa 1889; 5 cards (Box 8, Folder 294)
    - Arlatte & Cie., Cambrai, France, circa 1890; 2 cards (Box 8, Folder 295)
    - Au Bon Marche, Paris, France, circa 1900 (Box 9, Folder 296)
    - C. Beriot, Lille, France, circa 1890; 3 cards (Box 8, Folder 297)
    - C. Trampler, Lahr, Germany, circa 1900; 2 cards (Box 8, Folder 298)
    - Chicorée Boulangère Croissant, France, circa 1910; 2 cards (Box 8, Folder 299)
    - Chocolat Poulain, Blois, France, circa 1900 (Box 8, Folder 300)
    - Chocolates Figueras, Barcelona, Spain, circa 1900 (Box 8, Folder 301)
    - Dr. J. C. Ayer & Co., Lowell, Massachusetts, circa 1900 (Box 8, Folder 302)
    - Duroyon & Ramette, Cambrai, France, circa 1910 (Box 8, Folder 303)
    - Emile Bonzel, Haubourdin, France, circa 1910 (Box 8, Folder 304)
    - F. A. Sarg's Sohn & Co., Vienna, Austria, 1902 (Box 8, Folder 305)
    - F. Ad. Richter & Cie., Rudolstadt, Germany, circa 1905 (Box 8, Folder 306)
    - Hill, Moynan & Co., New York, New York, circa 1880; 5 cards (Box 8, Folder 307)
    - Joseph Lervilles, Bouchain, France, circa 1900 (Box 8, Folder 308)
    - Julius Braunlich, San Francisco, California, circa 1890 (Box 8, Folder 309)
    - Laboratories Rocher & Cie., Paris, France, circa 1900 (Box 8, Folder 310)
    - Maison des 100,000 Paletots, Bordeaux, France, circa 1900 (Box 8, Folder 311)
    - Paul Mairesse, Cambrai, France, circa 1900 (Box 8, Folder 312)
    - Publications Alcide Picard, Paris, France, circa 1910 (Box 8, Folder 313)
    - Saalestern Margarine, Germany, circa 1910 (Box 8, Folder 314)
    - The Daily Pioneer Press, Saint Paul, Minnesota, 1881 (Box 8, Folder 315)
    - Unidentified, circa 1880-1900; 17 cards (Box 8, Folder 316)
  - Sticker Books
    Books, generally intended for children, with pages that feature stickers affixed in formerly blank spaces as illustrations.
    Each folder contains a single sticker book, except where single or multiple stickers without a sticker book are noted.
    - Agência Portuguesa de Revistas
      - Raças Humanas (Human Race), 1956; 1 sticker (Box 9, Folder 317)
    - Archivo de Arte
      - El Legendario Far West (The Legendary Far West), 1966 (Box 9, Folder 318)
    - Associated British Foods
      - Indian Chiefs, 1972; 6 stickers (Box 9, Folder 319)
        Labels that accompanied jars of Ovaltine.
    - Baur's Bread
      - Portrait Trading Stamps, circa 1949; 100 stamps (Box 9, Folder 320)
    - Breda Fabriek van Suikerwerken
      - J. Victor Jansen, Volkeren-atlas, Amerika (Atlas of People, America), 1956 (Box 9, Folder 321)
    - Chocolat des Gourmets
      - Buffalo Bill, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 322)
    - Chocolates Ollé
      - Aventuras de Tom Sawyer, Album I, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 323)
      - Aventuras de Tom Sawyer, Album II, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 324)
      - Aventuras de Tom Sawyer, Album III, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 325)
      - Aventuras de Tom Sawyer, Album IV, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 326)
      - Aventuras de Tom Sawyer, Album V, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 327)
      - Aventuras de Tom Sawyer, Album VI, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 328)
    - D. C. Thomson & Co.
      Premiums from Hotspur, a boy's magazine
      - Danger Trail Picture Album No. 1: The Wildest Exploits of Buffalo Bill, 1938 March 4 (Box 9, Folder 329)
      - Danger Trail Picture Album No. 2: The Exploits of the Fighting Mounties, 1938 March 11; 1 booklet (Box 9, Folder 330)
    - Ediciones Cisne
      - Entre Pieles Rojas (Among Redskins), 1942 (Box 9, Folder 331)
    - Ediciones Generales
      - Album Lejano Oeste, No. 2 (Far West Album, No. 2), 1957 (Box 14, Folder 332)
        Lacks fourteen stickers.
    - Editions Hemma
      - Hommes Célèbres: Chef Indiens (Famous Men: Indian Chiefs), 1958; 1 sheet (Box 14, Folder 333)
        Sheet of uncut stickers.
    - Editorial Bruguera, S.A.
      - La Conquista del Oeste (How the West Was Wom), 1963 (Box 9, Folder 334)
    - Editorial Fher
      - Policia Montada del Canada (Canadian Mounted Police), 1940 (Box 9, Folder 335)
      - Indios (Indians), No. 115, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 336)
      - Rin-Tin-Tin en Cromos, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 337)
    - Editorial Novaro
      - Sonia Bleeker and Walter Kumme, Pieles Rojas (Redskins), translated by Ramón Rivera Caso, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 338)
        Also published as Indian Stamps by Simon & Schuster
    - Editorial Novaro-México
      - Costumbres del Cowboys (Customs of Cowboys), 1958 (Box 9, Folder 339)
    - Fritz Homann
      - Geschichte unserer Welt (Outline of History), 1951; 7 stickers (Box 9, Folder 340)
    - Gordon Bread
      - Good Neighbors of the Americas, circa 1950; 1 sticker (Box 9, Folder 341)
    - Great Northern Railway Company (U.S.)
      - See America First, Series No. 1, circa 1910; 10 stamps (Box 10, Folder 342)
      - See America First, Series No. 2, circa 1910; 10 stamps (Box 10, Folder 343)
      - See America First, Series No. 3, circa 1910; 10 stamps (Box 10, Folder 344)
      - See America First, Series No. 5, circa 1915; 12 stamps (Box 10, Folder 345)
      - See America First, Series No. 6, circa 1915; 10 stamps (Box 10, Folder 346)
      - See America First, Series No. 8, 1915-1916; 12 stamps (Box 10, Folder 347)
    - Nashua Gummed & Coated Paper Company
      - Nashua Indian Brand Gummed Paper Poster Stamps, circa 1916; 6 stamps (Box 10, Folder 348)
    - Onno Behrends Tea
      - Mit Karl Friedrich May im Wilden Westen (Karl May Wild West), 1951 (Box 10, Folder 349)
    - The Modern Boy Magazine
      - The Modern Boy Picture Album, circa 1930 (Box 10, Folder 350)
    - Tobler & Co.
      - Vivo ed Okupado dil Indiani (Lives and Occupations of Indians), circa 1925; 6 stamps (Box 10, Folder 351)
    - Union Pacific Railroad Company
      - The Overland Route Series, circa 1912; 10 stamps (Box 10, Folder 352)
    - Unidentified, circa 1940; 3 stickers (Box 10, Folder 353)
  - Sheet Music
    Printed music with illustrations and content that reflect American themes.
    - W. Lewis, Deerfoot Galop (London: Hopwood & Crew), 1870 (Box 14, Folder 354)
  - Printed Ephemera
    Arranged alphabetically by format and then alphabetically by publisher or company.
    Printed ephemera consisting of advertisements, booklets, books, coloring books, comic books, cutouts, newspapers, postcards, and serials.
    - Advertisements
      - Ciclop
        - Counter Card Advertisement, circa 1930 (Box 10, Folder 355)
          A cardboard point of purchase sign that depicts a cowboy holding a flashlight.
      - Régie Française des Tabacs
        - Card Advertisement for Cigarettes Balto and Gitanes, 1934 (Box 10, Folder 356)
      - Valaldo
        - Cigar Box Label, circa 1900 (Box 10, Folder 357)
      - Unidentified Italian Manufacturer
        - Illustrated Boxes for Color Pencils, circa 1960 (Box 10, Folder 358)
    - Booklets
      - Amalgamated Press, Ltd.
        - Half-a-million Redskins on the Warpath, circa 1940 (Box 10, Folder 359)
      - D. C. Thomson & Co.
        - The King's Empire, The Boys' Coronation Library, 1937 April 1 (Box 10, Folder 360)
      - National Biscuit Company
        - Heroes of the Wild West, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 361)
    - Books
      - Editorial Molino, Obras de Karl Friedrich May (Works of Karl Friedrich May)
        - Karl Friedrich May, En La Boca del Lobo (In the Mouth of the Wolf), 1937 (Box 10, Folder 362)
        - Karl Friedrich May, La Casa de la Muerte (House of Death), 1937 (Box 10, Folder 363)
        - Karl Friedrich May, La Montaña De Oro (The Mountain of Gold), 1937 (Box 11, Folder 364)
        - Karl Friedrich May, La Venganza Del Caudillo (Revenge From Caudillo), 1937 (Box 11, Folder 365)
      - Gran Album Almanaque Coyote 1946 (Great Album Coyote Almanac 1946), circa 1980 (Box 14, Folder 366)
        Facsimile of sticker books from 1946.
    - Coloring Books
      - Oxo Limited
        - Traditional Dress in Other Lands, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 367)
    - Comic Books
      - Argos
        - Los Pioneros de Kentucky (Kentucky Pioneers), 1968 (Box 11, Folder 368)
      - Editorial Bruguera, S.A.
        Issues in the series Joyas Literarias Juveniles (Youth Literary Jewels)
        - Jules Verne, La Vuelta al Mundo en Ochenta Días (Around the World in Eighty Days), Issue No. 17., 1971 (Box 11, Folder 369)
        - Harriet Beecher Stowe, La Cabaña de Tío Tom (Uncle Tom's Cabin), Issue No. 18, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 370)
        - William O'Connor, Buffalo Bill, Issue No. 29, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 371)
        - Karl Friedrich May, Entre Apaches y Comanches (Between Apaches and Comanches), Issue No. 36, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 372)
        - Karl Friedrich May, Entre Chacales (Between Jackals), Issue No. 45, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 373)
        - Thomas Mayne Reid, La Reina de los Lagos (Queen of the Lakes), Issue No. 61, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 374)
        - Karl Friedrich May, Botin de Saqueo (Booty Plunder), Issue No. 87, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 375)
        - Karl Friedrich May, Trampa de Cactus (Cactus Trap), Issue No. 122, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 376)
        - Karl Friedrich May, El Diablo de la Pradera (The Devil on the Prairie), Issue No. 139, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 377)
        - Karl Friedrich May, El Valle de los Osos (Bear Valley), Issue No. 141, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 378)
        - Karl Friedrich May, El Tesoro del Lago la Plata (The Treasure of Silver Lake), Issue No. 55, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 379)
        - Emilio Salgari, La Soberana del Campo de Oro (The Sovereign of the Gold Field), Issue No. 153, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 380)
        - Thomas Mayne Reid, Aventura en el Mississippi (Mississippi Adventure), Issue No. 159, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 381)
        - Karl Friedrich May, Prisionero de Los Ogallallas (sic) (Prisoners of the Ogallallas), Issue No. 163, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 382)
        - Karl Friedrich May, El Espiritu de Llano Estacado (The Ghost of Llano Estacado), Issue No. 172, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 383)
        - Karl Friedrich May, La Venganza de Winnetou (Winnetou's Revenge), Issue No. 173, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 384)
        - Karl Friedrich May, En La Boca del Lobo (In the Mouth of the Wolf), No. 176, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 385)
        - Karl Friedrich May, A Merced de un Pistolero (A Mercy of a Gunman), No. 180, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 386)
      - Editorial Valenciana
        - Manuel Gago García, Los Tres Amigos de Morten con el Pequeño Luchador (The Three Friends of Morten with the Little Fighter), Issue No. 203, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 387)
    - Cutouts
      - D.I.P.L.O.
        - Tribu e Genti d'America, I. Cheyennes (a Cavalio) (Tribes and People of America, I. Cheyennes (Cavalry)), circa 1950; 1 sheet (Box 14, Folder 388)
      - Ediciones Toray
        - Recortables Toray, Grupo 11, Oeste (Cut Toray, Group 11, West), 1962; 1 volume (Box 14, Folder 389)
      - Edizioni Marca Stella
        - Indiani Comanche, Foglio No. 23 (Comanche Indians, Sheet No. 23), circa 1950 (Box 14, Folder 390)
        - Indiani Irochesi, Foglio No. 24 and 33 (Iroquois Indians, Sheet No. 24 and 33), circa 1950 (Box 14, Folder 391)
      - Kellogg Company
        Cutouts from Sugar Stars or Sugar Pops.
        - Famous Indian Chiefs, 1962; 12 cutouts (Box 11, Folder 392)
        - Men of the Wild West, 1963; 12 cutouts (Box 11, Folder 393)
      - National Biscuit Company
        Cutouts from Shredded Wheat boxes.
        - Straight Arrow Injun-uities - Book One, 1949; 36 cutouts (Box 12, Folder 394)
        - Straight Arrow Injun-uities - Book Two, 1950; 36 cutouts (Box 12, Folder 395)
        - Straight Arrow Injun-uities - Book Three, 1951; 36 cutouts (Box 12, Folder 396)
        - Straight Arrow Injun-uities - Book Four, 1952; 36 cutouts (Box 12, Folder 397)
      - Unidentified
        - The Wild West, circa 1960; 12 cutouts (Box 12, Folder 398)
    - Newspapers
      - Il Papagallo (Bologna, Italy), 1879 May 18 (Box 14, Folder 399)
        Complete issue of an Italian humor newspaper that includes a color lithograph of a political cartoon depicting international pitfalls facing Great Britain.
    - Postcards
      - Gale & Polden, Photographic Postcards Related to an Indian Village at Earl's Court, circa 1907 (Box 12, Folder 400)
    - Serials
      - Ediciones Marco, Sitting-Bull, El Ultimo Piel Rosa (Sitting Bull, The Last Redskin)
        - No. 2, Combate Fantastico (Fantastic Fight), circa 1945 (Box 13, Folder 401)
        - No. 6, El Valle Fantastico (The Fantastic Valley), circa 1945 (Box 13, Folder 402)
        - No. 8, La Tumba de Las Luces Rojas (The Tomb of the Red Lights), circa 1945 (Box 13, Folder 403)
        - No. 13, Un Combate a Muerte (A Death Match), circa 1945 (Box 13, Folder 404)